Wilson, Ernest Henry, 1876-1930. Papers of Ernest Henry Wilson, 1896-1952: Guide.
Papers of Ernest Henry Wilson, 1896-1952.
- W.XIV: Ernest Henry Wilson Correspondence, 1899-1930., This correspondence series is divided into six subseries: A-F. Boxes: 15-19.
  - Subseries W.XIV:A: Letters written by Ernest Henry Wilson in the field to the Arnold Arboretum. Most of the letters are addressed to Charles Sprague Sargent; a few are addressed to Alfred Rehder. Arranged chronologically. 1906-1922.
    - Box 21, NOTE: Folders 8-10 contain letters written by Wilson during his sixth expedition to the Far East. 1917-1919. (67 letters total); NOTE: Folders 11-15 contain letters written by Wilson to the Arnold Arboretum during his expedition to the Southern Hemisphere. "The Gardens of the World." 1
      - Folder 1
        - From London and Kew, August-September 1906. (8 letters), Handwritten version: http://nrs.harvard.edu/urn-3:ARB.JPLIB:2562596.; Transcribed version: http://nrs.harvard.edu/urn-3:ARB.JPLIB:4516632.
      - Folder 2
        - From Oakland, CA, January 1907. (1 letter), Handwritten version: http://nrs.harvard.edu/urn-3:ARB.JPLIB:2562597.; Transcribed version: http://nrs.harvard.edu/urn-3:ARB.JPLIB:4646393.
      - Folder 3
        - From China, February-December 1907. (17 letters), Handwritten version: http://nrs.harvard.edu/urn-3:ARB.JPLIB:2562598.; Transcribed version: http://nrs.harvard.edu/urn-3:ARB.JPLIB:4646395.
      - Folder 4
        - From China, January 1908-April 1909. (29 letters) (Includes copy of letter to Messrs. Veitch, 1909), Handwritten version: http://nrs.harvard.edu/urn-3:ARB.JPLIB:2640209.; Transcribed version: http://nrs.harvard.edu/urn-3:ARB.JPLIB:4661951.
      - Folder 5
        - From England, 1909. (12 letters), Handwritten version: http://nrs.harvard.edu/urn-3:ARB.JPLIB:2640210.; Transcribed version: http://nrs.harvard.edu/urn-3:ARB.JPLIB:4669677.
      - Folder 6
        - From China, June 1910-February 1911. (13 letters), Handwritten version: http://nrs.harvard.edu/urn-3:ARB.JPLIB:2640211.; Transcribed version: http://nrs.harvard.edu/urn-3:ARB.JPLIB:4676289.
      - Folder 7
        - From Japan, February 1914-January 1915. (34 letters), Handwritten version: http://nrs.harvard.edu/urn-3:ARB.JPLIB:2562599.; Transcribed version: http://nrs.harvard.edu/urn-3:ARB.JPLIB:4677290.
      - Folder 8
        - To Charles Sprague Sargent and Alfred Rehder, 1917. (19 letters), Handwritten version: http://nrs.harvard.edu/urn-3:ARB.JPLIB:2562600.; Transcribed version: http://nrs.harvard.edu/urn-3:ARB.JPLIB:4677654.
      - Folder 9
        - To Charles Sprague Sargent and Alfred Rehder, 1918. (41 letters), Handwritten version: http://nrs.harvard.edu/urn-3:ARB.JPLIB:2562601.; Transcribed version: http://nrs.harvard.edu/urn-3:ARB.JPLIB:4692499.
      - Folder 10
        - To Charles Sprague Sargent, 1919. (7 letters), Handwritten version: http://nrs.harvard.edu/urn-3:ARB.JPLIB:2562602.; Transcribed version: http://nrs.harvard.edu/urn-3:ARB.JPLIB:4695651.
      - Folder 11
        - From England and Australia, 1920. (20 letters)
      - Folder 12
        - From Australia and New Zealand, 1921. (20 letters)
      - Folder 13
        - From India, 1921. (17 letters)
      - Folder 14
        - From South Africa, November 1921-1922. (9 letters)
      - Folder 15
        - From England, 1922. (21 letters)
    - Box 22
      - Spiral bound transcriptions of letters for the years: 1906-1922, 1914-1915, 1917-1919. Duplicate transcriptions of letters for the years: 1906-1908, 1910, 1914, 1917-1918.
  - Subseries W.XIV:B: Letters received by EHW from James, Harry J., and George H. Veitch, 1899-1913. Arranged chronologically.
    - Box 23
      - Folder 1
        - From James Veitch, 1899-1902. (36 letters)
        - Torn newspaper clippings. One dated February 23, 1901.
      - Folder 2
        - From James Veitch, 1903. (12 letters)
      - Folder 3
        - From James Veitch, 1904. (12 letters)
      - Folder 4
        - From James Veitch, 1905-1907. (4 letters)
      - Folder 5
        - From Harry J. Veitch, 1906-1913. (10 letters)
      - Folder 6
        - From George Harrow Veitch, 1913. (3 letters) (EHW comment on July 4 letter)
      - Folder 7
        - Golden Wedding Commemoration Studio Card with Portrait Photographs of Sir Harry and Lady Veitch, 1917.
  - Subseries W.XIV:C: Letters (copies) and postcards written by Ernest Henry Wilson, 1907-1910, 1922-1930.
    In some cases Wilson's letter is copied on verso of a letter received. In other cases Wilson's letter is filed with a letter received. One or two letters unless otherwise indicated. Arranged chronologically.
    - Box 24
      - Folder 1
        - To Messrs. Dodwell & Co., Shanghai, 1907.
      - Folder 2
        - To David Fairchild, Washington, DC, 1907.
      - Folder 3
        - To William W. Rockwill, Peking, 1907.
      - Folder 4
        - To Frank Meyer, 1907. (Letter of instructions for Meyer's Wu t'ai expedition)
      - Folder 5
        - To Messrs. Farquhar, Boston. 1908-1909.
      - Folder 6
        - To Miss Ellen Willmott, England, 1908-1909.
      - Folder 7
        - To W.J. Tutcher, Hong Kong, 1910.
      - Folder 8
        - To Yokohama Nurseries, Japan, 1919-1930. (5 letters)
      - Folder 9
        - Letters to C.T. White, Brisbane, Australia, 1922-1928.
      - Folder 10
        - To John E. Thayer, Boston, 1922.
      - Folder 11
        - To W. Wright Smith, Edinburgh, 1924-1928.
      - Folder 12
        - To Frederick V. Coville, Washington, DC, 1925.
      - Folder 13
        - To H.E. Allanson, Washington, DC, 1926.
      - Folder 14
        - To Mrs. Charles Ripley, Dorchester, MA, 1926, 1930.
      - Folder 15
        - To J.F. Rock, China, 1927. (6 letters)
      - Folder 16
        - Letters to The Royal Horticultural Society, 1927.
      - Folder 17
        - To G.B. Burtnett, Los Angeles, CA, 1928.
      - Folder 18
        - To Erling Christophersen, Norway, 1928.
      - Folder 19
        - To A.C. Hoffman, Rochester, NY, 1928.
      - Folder 20
        - To E.J. Palmer, MO, 1928.
      - Folder 21
        - To A. Grove, London, 1928-1929. (3 letters in reference to Lilium nomenclature)
      - Folder 22
        - To John H. Taylor, Harvard University, 1928-1929. (6 letters)
      - Folder 23
        - To Joseph E.I. Perry, Worcester, MA, 1928-1929.
      - Folder 24
        - To C.P. Horsford, VT, 1928-1930. (11 letters)
      - Folder 25
        - To Professor Oakes Ames, 1928-1930. (8 letters)
      - Folder 26
        - To J. W. Besant, Ireland, 1929.
      - Folder 27
        - To Alex P. Dewar, Boston, MA, 1929.
      - Folder 28
        - To N. Nakai, Tokyo, Japan, 1929.
      - Folder 29
        - To Houghton Mifflin, Boston, MA, 1929.
      - Folder 30
        - To Mrs. M.S. Anderson, GA, 1930. (3 letters)
      - Folder 31
        - To E. Long, India, 1930. (5 letters)
      - Folder 32
        - To George F. Napier, England, 1930. Napier was a staff officer in Ichang, China in 1900.
      - Folder 33
        - To B.W. Hunt, University of Georgia, 1930.
      - Folder 34
        - To Mrs. Ernest Henry Wilson: 3 postcards; unsent postcard, 1917, no date.
  - Subseries W.XIV:D: Official correspondence with the administration of Harvard University during Ernest Henry Wilson's months of working as "assistant director in charge," after Charles Sprague Sargent's death in 1927.
    - Box 24
      - Folder 1
        - March-May 1927.
      - Folder 2
        - Copy of EHW's seven page report to Prof. Oakes Ames, Supervisor, on the work and progress of the Arnold Arboretum during the fiscal year ending June 30, 1926. Signed "Keeper," dated 1927.
  - Subseries W.XIV:E: Letters received by Ernest Henry Wilson and Mrs. Wilson: 1906, l907, 1916-1930. One or two letters from each correspondent, unless otherwise indicated. Arranged alphabetically., NOTE: See also the Arnold Arboretum's general letter file.
    - Box 24
      - Folder 1
        - From Outram Bangs, 1906.
      - Folder 2
        - From L.C. Bobbink, 1930.
      - Folder 3
        - From James Boyd, Pennsylvania Horticultural Society, 1927.
      - Folder 4
        - From Myron Converse, 1930.
      - Folder 5
        - From Charles Eley, 1916.
      - Folder 6
        - From the Emperor of Japan. 1917.
      - Folder 7
        - From John K.M.L. Farquhar, 1921.
      - Folder 8
        - From Alvan Fuller, 1926.
      - Folder 9
        - From the Herbst Bros., 1929.
      - Folder 10
        - From C.W. Hoitt, 1922.
      - Folder 11
        - From Gerald W. Loder, 1922.
      - Folder 12
        - From J. Horace McFarland, 1930.
      - Folder 13
        - From Frank Meyer, 1907. (4 letters of special interest from China)
      - Folder 14
        - From John Millais, 1924.
      - Folder 15
        - From Mi .. ng, E.G., no date. (Governor's House, Ottawa) (Signature cannot be identified)
      - Folder 16
        - From Henry Morgan, 1930.
      - Folder 17
        - From C.C. Robertson, 1923.
      - Folder 18
        - From Wilhelm Robinson, 1925-1930.
      - Folder 19
        - From Charles Sprague Sargent, 1906-1908. (Copies of letters from Sargent to EHW in China, and 24 original letters)
      - Folder 20
        - From Charles Sprague Sargent, 1908-1918. (Copies of letters from Sargent to EHW in China, and 47 original letters)
      - Folder 21
        - From Charles Sprague Sargent, 1920-1921. (2 original letters to EHW in South Africa)
      - Folder 22
        - From G.R. Shaw, no date.
      - Folder 23
        - From William Stewart, 1918.
      - Folder 24
        - From Mark N. Trollope, 1926.
      - Folder 25
        - From John Vilmorin, no date.
      - Folder 26
        - Frances Kindon Ward, 1919.
      - Folder 27
        - John C. Williams, 1907, 1916-1930.
      - Folder 28
        - From A. Wilson, 1930.
  - Subseries W.XIV:F: Letters written by Ernest Henry Wilson to Harlan Page Kelsey between 1913-1930. Arranged chronologically.
    - Box 25
      - Folder 1
        - From Charles Sprague Sargent to Harlan Page Kelsey, 1913, sent with the Veitch list of "New hardy plants from Western China introduced through Mr. E.H. Wilson." The list is checked by staff at the Arnold Arboretum. (2 letters)
      - Folder 2
        - 1922-1914. (22 letters)
      - Folder 3
        - 1925-1926. (43 letters)
      - Folder 4
        - 1927-1930. (46 letters)
        - Also loose in box, 4 notecards and business card of Henry T. Moon for copies of "America's Greatest Garden."
- W.XV: Published material about Ernest Henry Wilson (1902-present) and monographs by and about Wilson (1916-1993)., Articles are arranged in chronological order.
  - Box 26
    - Folder 1
      - Clippings about EHW's expeditions, 1902-1932.
    - Folder 2
      - Bullard, F. Lauriston, "A museum of living trees: The Arnold Arboretum, of Harvard University, which is gathering every tree and shrub in the world that will grow in the latitude of Boston—the Daring Work of its Explorers in Western China and Tibet," The World's Work 21 (1910-1911). pp. 14147-14158.
    - Folder 3
      - Clippings on honors and awards presented to EHW, 1912-1930.
    - Folder 4
      - Additional clippings on EHW, 1912-1930.
    - Folder 5
      - "Chinese Wilson—Plant hunter," The World's Work (1913) (2 copies)
    - Folder 6
      - Articles on EHW's expedition to Japan, 1914-1915.
    - Folder 7
      - Clippings on lecture by EHW on "Flowers of Japan," Boston Transcript (1916).
    - Folder 8
      - Articles on EHW's expedition to Japan, Korea, Formosa, 1919.
    - Folder 9
      - Articles on the "Kurume Azaleas," 1920.
    - Folder 10
      - Articles on EHW's expedition to the Southern Hemisphere, the "Gardens of the World," 1920-1922.
    - Folder 11
      - Clippings saved by EHW from newspapers in the Southern Hemisphere, 1920-1922. Includes The Australian Forestry Journal, 8:2 (February 1925). With Wilson's picture on the cover, and notation on p. 33. Also includes Cockayne, Leonard. "Professor E.H. Wilson on New Zealand Forests and Forestry," [proof] New Zealand Journal of Science and Technology, (1921?).
    - Folder 12
      - Clippings on lectures given by EHW upon his return from the Southern Hemisphere, 1922-1924.
    - Folder 13
      - Book reviews of books written by EHW, 1925-1929.
    - Folder 14
      - EHW obituaries, 1930.
    - Folder 15
      - Articles on EHW, 1931-1932.
    - Folder 16
      - Various periodical articles, mainly on EHW's plant introductions, 1918-1952.
    - Folder 17
      - Pamphlet titled, Ernest H. Wilson, by the Garden Club of America, January 21-March 7, 1941.
      - Edwards, Vincent. "Columbus of the Plant World," Forward, (1940s?).
    - Folder 18
      - White, William Chapman. "Just about Everything: The Lily and the Broken Leg" New York Herald Tribune, (June 25, 1954).
      - Aldredge, James. "'Chinese' Wilson, Columbus of the Plant World," New England Homestead, (1958).
    - Folder 19
      - Pamphlet titled, Excerpts: Letters of C.S. Sargent to Rochester Park Personnel, 1961.
      - Doleshy, Frank. "Distribution and Ecology of Certain Japanese Rhododendrons: A Progress Report," Quarterly Bulletin of the American Rhododendron Society, (July 1968).
      - Tanner, Anne. (Book Review) "In Flowery Praise of Chinese Wilson," Rochester Democrat and Chronicle, (September 28, 1969).
      - Hall, G.K. "Index to American Botanical Literature, 1886-1966" Torrey Botanical Club, (1969).
    - Folder 20
      - Arnoldia, (May 1972).
      - "Salute to the Arboretum on its Centennial," Boston Globe, May 21,1972.
    - Folder 21
      - "Craftman's Concrete: Sir Gordon Russell's Garden at Kingcombe, Chipping Campden." Concrete Quarterly 98, (July-September 1973) pp. 33-35.
    - Folder 22
      - Rose, Dorothy. "'Chinese' Wilson, Plant-Hunter," Country Life, June 3, 1976.
      - Chvany, Peter J. "E.H. Wilson: Photographer" Arnoldia, 36:5 (September/October 1976). (2 copies)
    - Folder 23
      - Loke, Margarett. "Glimpses of Old China," New York Times, (April 30, 1978).
    - Folder 24
      - Arnoldia, 40:3 (May/June 1980). (3 copies) Includes article by Richard Howard, "E.H. Wilson as a Botanist (Part 1)," and article by Kristen Clausen and Shui-Ying Hu, "Mapping the Collecting Localities of E.H. Wilson in China."
      - Arnoldia, 40:4, (July/August 1980). Includes article by Richard Howard, "E. H. Wilson as a Botanist (Part 2)."
      - Howard, R.A. "E.H. Wilson and the 'Nodding Lilac'" Yearbook of the Lilac Society, 9 (1980). pp. 13-15. Includes original artwork for the four maps published in the article.
    - Folder 25
      - Pollack, Lori. "Walking Through China in Search of Plants," The Morton Arboretum Quarterly, 19:3 (Autumn 1983).
    - Folder 26
      - "Arduous Trek Through China for Beauty," The Boston Globe, (May 6, 1985).
      - Blithewold Gardens & Arboretum Newsletter, 6:4 (Fall 1985).
      - Reed, Christopher. "Lilies for 'Chinese Wilson", Harvard Magazine, (March/April 1986).
      - "Arboretum Heads Down 'Chinese' Path," Harvard Gazette, (February 6, 1987).
    - Folder 27
      - "The Closer You Get to the 'Rhodies,' the Better They Look," Smithsonian, 17:2 (May 1986). pp. 52-62. With photograph of Wilson and mention of him as one of the first rhododendron hunters to collect for an American institution.
    - Folder 28
      - Heriz-Smith, Shirley. "Choicest Chinese Take-Away: Ernest Wilson, Plant Collector," in Country Life, (May 18, 1989). pp. 256-260.
      - "Moments in Time," Harvard Magazine, 92:2, (November/December 1989). pp. 46- 47. Featuring Wilson's photograph in Japan of Prunus subhirtella pendula.
    - Folder 29
      - Tozer, Eliot. "On the Trail of E.H. Wilson," Horticulture, 72:9 (November 1994). pp. 50-58. (3 copies, incomplete)
    - Folder 30
      - Brochure, The Asia center at Harvard University, 2001, with two notes inside (from Sarah O'Brien Mackey and Noelehua Lyons) regarding the cover photograph (taken by Wilson in 1908).
      - Arnoldia, 61:3 (2002). Includes "Wilson's Lost Tree" by Mark Flanagan and "Across the Chino-Thibetan [sic] Borderland [1908]" by E.H. Wilson.
      - Hobson, Katherine. "Green Dreams: A plant collector's quest for rarities," U.S. News and World Report, 136:7 (February 23/March 1, 2004).
    - Folder 31
      - Undated clippings, including "Ripley's Believe It or Not!" cartoon panel on Wilson's 1903 leg injury.
    - Folder 32
      - Copy of Arnoldia, 36:5, (September/October 1976). Interleaved proofs and negatives of images published in issue. Including additional negatives; color prints from the Birmingham Botanical Garden—the Wilson Border, 1989; and one slide.
    - Folder 33
      - "Editorial: Ernest Henry Wilson" and "Books by Ernest H. Wilson: A Memorial List" both from Landscape Architecture XXI:3, April 1931.
    - Bound Volumes
      - Wilson, Ernest Henry. A Naturalist in Western China, Volumes I and II, 1913.
      - Wilson, Ernest Henry. The Cherries of Japan 1916. Publications of the Arnold Arboretum, No. 7.
      - Wilson, Ernest Henry.“Indigenous Forest Trees of Kenya.” The Farmer’s Journal; Vol 4, No 8; 23 February, 1922.
      - Wilson, Ernest Henry and Alfred Rehder, A Monograph of Azaleas, 1921. S. McKelvey’s copy, labeled with her name on inside cover; no additional notes or annotations.
      - Wilson, Ernest Henry. America's greatest garden: the Arnold arboretum / by E. H. Wilson; with frontispiece and fifty illustrations mostly by the author. Boston, Mass.: The Stratford Company, 1925. Includes two notes from Clara F. Clapp about donating the book to the Arboretum, and referencing two letters from Wilson to her grandmother, Mrs. Charles Ripley (see Subseries W.XIII:C Folder 14)
      - Wilson, Ernest Henry. Plant hunting / by Ernest H. Wilson; with 128 illustrations, mostly from photographs taken by the author. Boston, Mass.: The Stratford company, 1927. Two volume set, autographed copy. "To his most energetic friend, W. Ormiston Roy, with affectionate regards these volumes are inscribed by the author, Sept 7th, 1927." Includes a letter from Wilson to Roy about the book, and three copies of book reviews Wilson sent to Roy.
      - Rehder, Alfred. "Ernest Henry Wilson," Journal of the Arnold Arboretum, XI:4 (October 1930). Bound copy.
      - Farrington, Edward I. (Edward Irving). Ernest H. Wilson, plant hunter. With a list of his most important introductions and where to get them. Boston, Mass., The Stratford Company [c1931]. (2 copies, 1 signed by author)
      - The flowering world of "Chinese" Wilson. Edited and with introd. and brief biography by Daniel J. Foley. [New York], Macmillan, c1969. (2 copies)
      - Tree Calendar 1978. Featuring the photographs of Ernest H. Wilson, Interior Provinces of Hupeh and Szechuan between 1907 and 1910.
      - Briggs, Roy W. "Chinese" Wilson: a life of Ernest H. Wilson, 1876-1930 / Roy W. Briggs; foreword by Roy Lancaster. London: HMSO, c1993.
- Series W.XVI: Collected Works: selected published articles, excluding monographs, 1901-1953, This series is subdivided into three subseries, A-C.
  - Subseries W.XVI:A: Articles written or compiled by Ernest Henry Wilson. Arranged chronologically.
    - Box 27
      - Folder 1
        - Unwin, F.S., commissioner of customs, Ichang, Hupeh.ICHANG-Decennial report, 1892-1901. Includes "Note of the Flora of Western Hupeh" written by Wilson. pp. 191-198. Also, photocopy of pages 191-198.
      - Folder 2
        - "Service held in St. Paul's Cathedral...In Memory of his late Majesty King Edward, May 20, 1910." The Journal of the Kew Guild, (1897). Thought to be compiled by EHW.
      - Folder 3
        - Clippings from The Gardeners' Chronicle, 1903-1904, complied by EHW. Mainly on plant introductions collected by Wilson in China and introduced by Messrs. Veitch, 43 p. (Moved from the Arnold Arboretum library Ve. W693.3W).
      - Folder 4
        - "Leaves from my Chinese notebook." Bound series of clippings from The Gardeners' Chronicle, 1905-1906. 76 p. Gift of E.H. Wilson's daughter Muriel Wilson Slate. Dates of publication inserted at end. Specimen label notes inserted at end. Transferred from the Botany Libraries, February 2009.
        - Another copy, incomplete. Annotated by Ivan M. Johnson.
        - Photocopies of the original articles in Gardeners' Chronicle.
      - Folder 5
        - "Wanderings in China." Journal of the Horticultural Society, 29:3 (1905). 7 p.
      - Folder 6
        - "Western China: A Field for Sportsmen." The Field, The Country Gentleman's Newspaper 106 (October 7, 1905).
      - Folder 7
        - "Some new Chinese plants." Bulletin of Miscellaneous Information (Royal Gardens, Kew), 1906:5 (1906). pp. 147-163. (2 copies)
      - Folder 8
        - Wilson, Ernest Henry. "T'ang-Shên. (Codonopsis Tangshen, Oliv.),"Bulletin of Miscellaneous Information (Royal Gardens, Kew), 1907:1 (1907). p. 9.
      - Folder 9
        - "The Chinese Flora." Journal of the Horticultural Society, 33:2 (1908). 6 p. (2 copies)
      - Folder 10
        - "E.H. Wilson: Address to members of the Massachusetts Horticultural Society. The fourth expedition taken to China for the purpose of collecting new plants for the Arnold Arboretum." Reprint from the Boston Transcript, (November 4, 1911).
      - Folder 11
        - "New Chinese Plants," Horticulture (November 4, 1911). Proofs.
      - Folder 12
        - "Kingdom of Flowers," National Geographic Magazine, 22:11 (November 1911). (3 copies)
      - Folder 13
        - Sargent, Charles Sprague. A guide to the Arnold Arboretum. Cambridge, 1911.
        - The Arnold Arboretum: The C. S. Sargent Memorial Fund for the Endowment of the Arnold Arboretum. January 1928.
        - Arnold Arboretum Harvard University: Plan of the Arnold Arboretum. No date.
      - Folder 14
        - Wilson, Ernest Henry. A Naturalist in Western China: With vasculum, camera, and gun. Preface by Ernest Henry Wilson and Introduction by Charles Sprague Sargent, New York: Doubleday, Page, & Co. 1913. Excerpted pp. vii-xxxvii.
      - Folder 15
        - "Consider the Lilies," The Garden Magazine, 21:6 (July 1915).
      - Folder 16
        - "A summary report on the forests, forest trees, and afforestation in Chosen." Transactions of Royal Scottish Arboricultural Society, (1919). 8 p.
      - Folder 17
        - “Citizens of Tokyo, Save Your Cherry Trees,” Sakura, (1919). 3p.
      - Folder 18
        - "Kurume Azaleas." Bulletin of the Massachusetts Horticultural Society, 33 (1920). 4 p.
      - Folder 19
        - Wilson, Ernest Henry. "The Romance of Our Trees—IX: Whence Came the Common Fruits?" The Garden Magazine, XXXI:4 (June 1920). pp. 259-263.
      - Folder 20
        - "Acacias." Bulletin of the Massachusetts Horticultural Society, 11 (1923). 8 p.
      - Folder 21
        - Wilson, Ernest Henry. "Autumn Landscapes," Christian Science Monitor, (October 8, 1923).
        - Wilson, Ernest Henry. "The Dawn of Spring," Christian Science Monitor,(April 11, 1924).
        - Wilson, Ernest Henry. "Cherry Blossom Time," Christian Science Monitor, (May 19, 1924).
        - Wilson, Ernest Henry. "The Lilacs Are in Bloom," Christian Science Monitor, (June 2, 1924).
        - Wilson, Ernest Henry. "Work of Arnold Arboretum," Christian Science Monitor, no date.
      - Folder 22
        - Wilson, Ernest Henry. “Harvard’s Tree Museum,” Museum Work, (January-February, 1924). COPY.
      - Folder 23
        - Articles by EHW from Horticulture, 1923-1930. Thought to be compiled by E.H. Wilson.
    - Box 28
      - Folder 1
        - List of EHW articles published in House and Gardens, 1924-1930.
        - List of contributions to House and Gardens, 1924-1930.
      - Folder 2
        - "Price of the Regal Lily: A treasure wrested from forbidding Tibet," The Country Gentleman, (October 1925).
      - Folder 3